minds.com 2014-07-01

# Privacy | Minds

1\.  The right to access and change the free and open source code powering the apps that you are interacting with.

2\.  The right to create an anonymous account and use proxy servers to connect to Minds.  This is essential for ensuring you aren't tracked or spied upon.

3\.  The right to remix.  All content is licensed openly and Minds code is free and open source software.

4\.  The right to access all human knowledge.

5\.  The right to vote on Internet evolution.

6\.  The right to freedom of speech and the press.  Everything legal in the world is legal here.

7\.  The right to have your voice heard.  Anyone in the world can be featured.

8\.  The right to film, record and share your experience.

9\.  The right to make money from your work.

10\.  The right to peaceful gatherings and protests.

Welcome to the MINDS.com web site and online services.  MINDS values the privacy of our members and others who visit and use the MINDS.com Site (individually, "You" or collectively, "Users").  We take your privacy seriously and make it a priority to protect personally identifiable information that we obtain from and about individuals both online and offline.

This Privacy Policy describes what information we gather from you, how we use that information, and what we do to protect it. By using the MINDS.com Site (whether or not you are a registered member), you expressly consent to the information handling practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not want information about you to be used in the manner set forth in this Privacy Policy, please do not use the MINDS.com Site.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and is subject to the MINDS Terms of Service Your use of MINDS and any personal information you provide on the MINDS.com Site are subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy and the MINDS Terms of Service.

We want MINDS to be a network based on openness and sharing.  We also want nothing more than to protect your universal rights to anonymity and privacy.  In order to satisfy both of these elements, we allow people the freedom to create eponymous or anonymous accounts.  Impersonation however is expressly prohibited on the MINDS.com Site.  Spread of private information has the ability to affect populations in dramatic ways.  For this reason Minds.com is heavily encrypted and we have implemented a wide spectrum of security certificates and privacy settings to make sure everyone is as safe and secure as possible. At the end of the day though, we cannot offer a 100% guarantee that your messages won't be hacked.

Otherwise our mantra is "We have nothing to hide!" and all site data created here is licensed to the world under the[ Creative Commons](http://www.minds.com/web/20130806055502/http://creativecommons.org/licenses/)  and  [General Public License](http://www.minds.com/web/20130806055502/http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html) because we think that people have a right to such accessibility that is generally not allowed by other networks.  The main purpose of the internet is to share information.  This is how it grows and evolves.  The internet can't exist if we don't share our data, and the truth is that it is next to impossible to use the web without sharing your tracks.  Everything is streaming and being recorded somewhere, and it is up to you to keep this in your mind and share responsibly.

### Information Minds Collects

Information that you give us:  In order to use several of the services that we offer on MINDS, we require you to register an account.  When you register for the MINDS.com Site, we will ask you for a valid email address, a username, and some other basic information.

Information we get from your use of our services:  We may collect information about the services that you use and how you use them, like when you visit a website that uses our advertising services or you view and interact with our ads and content. This information includes:

  * Device information:  We may collect device-specific information (such as your hardware model, operating system version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information including phone number).

  * Log information:  When you use our services or view content provided by MINDS, we may automatically collect and store certain information in[ server logs](http://www.minds.com/web/20130806055502/http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/key-terms/#toc-terms-server-logs). This may include:details of how you used our service, such as your search queries.

  * Internet protocol address.

  * Device event information such as crashes, system activity, hardware settings, browser type, browser language, the date/time of your request and referral URL.

  * Cookies that may uniquely identify your browser or your MINDS Account.

  * Local storage:  We may collect and store information (including personal information) locally on your device using mechanisms such as browser web storage (including HTML 5) and application data caches.

  * Location information:  When you use a location-enabled MINDS service, we may collect and process information about your actual location, like GPS signals sent by a mobile device. We may also use various technologies to determine location, such as sensor data from your device that may, for example, provide information on nearby Wi-Fi access points and cell towers.

  * Cookies and anonymous identifiers:  We use various technologies to collect and store information when you visit MINDS, and this may include sending one or more[ cookies](http://www.minds.com/web/20130806055502/http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/key-terms/#toc-terms-cookie) or[ anonymous identifiers](http://www.minds.com/web/20130806055502/http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/key-terms/#toc-terms-identifier) to your device. We also use cookies and anonymous identifiers when you interact with services we offer to our partners, such as advertising services or MINDS features that may appear on other sites.

### How MINDS uses your information

  * MINDS collects personally identifiable information when you register as a member in order to establish and enhance our relationship with you. MINDS generally uses the information you provide or that we collect to operate, maintain, enhance, and provide all of the features and services found on the MINDS Site. We will use your email address, without further consent, for non-marketing or administrative purposes such as notifying you of major site updates.

  * MINDS uses all of the information that we collect from Users to understand and analyze the usage trends and preferences of our Users, to improve the way the MINDS Site works and looks, and to create new features and functionality.

  * MINDS may use "cookies" information to: (a) remember your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the MINDS Site; (b) monitor aggregate site usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed; and (c) track your entries, submissions, and status in any promotions or other activities.

  * MINDS will not share your personal information with advertisers or third parties.

### How Minds shares your information

We do not share personal information with companies, organizations and individuals outside of MINDS unless one of the following circumstances apply:

  * We will share personal information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of MINDS only when we have your consent to do so.

  * If your MINDS Account is managed for you by a[ domain administrator,](http://www.minds.com/web/20130806055502/http://support.google.com/a/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=178897) then your domain administrator and resellers who provide user support to your organization will have access to your MINDS Account information (including your email and other data). Your domain administrator may be able to:

    * View statistics regarding your account, like statistics regarding applications you install.

    * Change your account password.

    * Suspend or terminate your account access.

    * Access or retain information stored as part of your account.

    * Receive your account information in order to satisfy applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request.

    * Restrict your ability to delete or edit information or privacy settings.

  * We will share personal information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of MINDS if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to:

    * Meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request.

    * Enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations.

    * Detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues.

    * Protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of MINDS, our users or the public as required or permitted by law.

We may share aggregated, non-personally identifiable information publicly and with our partners – like publishers, advertisers or connected sites. For example, we may share information publicly to show trends about the general use of our services.

If MINDS is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, we will continue to ensure the confidentiality of any personal information or give affected users reasonable notice before personal information is transferred or becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

### Access Levels

Several features of the site offer users the ability to set access levels for their content.  It is the responsibilty to understand these options and choose the appropriate access level. When you select the ‘Public’ access level, your content will be viewable by everyone on the internet, and not just logged in users.  ‘Logged in Users’ will grant access to registered MINDS users, and your content will not be viewable by the general internet.  ‘Contacts’ will grant access only to those MINDS users who are on your contact list.  ‘Private’ will deny access to all other users.  You may also share content with particular groups that you are a member of.  Please understand these different access levels before posting content on MINDS.

### International Visitors:

The MINDS Site is hosted in the United States and is intended solely for visitors located within the United States.  If you nonetheless choose to use the MINDS Site from the European Union or other regions of the world with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, then please note that you are transferring your personally identifiable information outside of those regions to the United States and by providing your personally identifiable information on the MINDS Site you consent to that transfer.

### Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy:

This Privacy Policy may be revised periodically without further notice to you and this will be reflected by a "Last Modified" date above. If we make a material change that would enable us to use any information previously collected under this Privacy Policy in a less restrictive manner we will take reasonable steps to obtain your consent to any such new use or disclosure. Please revisit this page to stay aware of any changes. Your continued use of the MINDS Site constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any future revisions.

_Last Modified: March 9 , 2013_
